<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Home</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Home</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>A gentle introduction to data.table</title>
      <link>/post/2020-06-17-datatable-introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020-06-17-datatable-introduction/</guid>
      <description>This post presents a quick introduction to data.table, an indispensable package for data wrangling in R. The main objective is to present the data.table syntax, showing how to perform basic but essential data manipulation tasks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A data.table and pandas small stroll</title>
      <link>/post/2020-06-14-datatable-pandas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020-06-14-datatable-pandas/</guid>
      <description>data.table and pandas are two major libraries for efficient manipulation of data frames in R and Python, respectively. Being quite familiar with data.table, I wrote this post as an exercice to learn more about pandas. Commands to execute common data munging tasks are presented side-by-side to facilitate the comparison.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning Japanese with data.table and ggplot2</title>
      <link>/post/2019-06-16-learning-japanese/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-06-16-learning-japanese/</guid>
      <description>This post is about drawing hiragana and katakana tables using R, data.table, and ggplot2. The objective was to better illustrate the rules that underlie these two Japanese writing systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dendrograms in R, a lightweight approach</title>
      <link>/post/2019-06-08-lightweight-dendrograms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-06-08-lightweight-dendrograms/</guid>
      <description>I wanted a &amp;ldquo;lightweight&amp;rdquo; and flexible ggplot2-based solution to draw dendrograms, in particular with the possibility to highlight clusters using different branch colors. I finally ended up writing a small set of functions, using ggdendro and ggplot2 only.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Turning images into ridgeline plots</title>
      <link>/post/2019-05-18-images-to-ridges/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-05-18-images-to-ridges/</guid>
      <description>I was wondering what images turned into ridgeline plots would look like. This post illustrates some experiments performed with ggplot2 and ggridges.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A data.table and dplyr tour</title>
      <link>/post/2019-03-03-datatable-dplyr/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-03-03-datatable-dplyr/</guid>
      <description>data.table and dplyr are two R packages that both aim at an easier and more efficient manipulation of data frames. This article shows how they can be used to execute common data munging tasks. The commands are presented side-by-side to facilitate the comparison.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-studying Python and Machine Learning: 2018 in review</title>
      <link>/post/2019-01-15-2018-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2019-01-15-2018-learning/</guid>
      <description>Both for personal interest and professional development, I started to learn Python and machine learning concepts. This article summarizes my 2018 learning path.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>